[Music]
we live in a time where if we just focus
on the hard science of climate change we
could despair and say maybe it's already
too late but I don't think that that is
a way to live into the future
it's we need to now work miracles
because what is likely is unthinkable an
unconscionable so we really need to make
the impossible happen
[Music]
regenerative design of creating
regenerative cultures is bay building
the capacity of people in place to
respond to transformation and change in
ways that create a healthier more
vibrant more vital system that can move
on into the future
so regenerative cultures will look
different in every place there are
expressions that come out of the story
of place and the potential that each
place has both socially economically and
ecologically and the core element is to
basically work with people and build
their capacity to manifest that
potential so it's really a key point in
human history if we don't take this
window of opportunity which is the next
two three four five years to begin a
long journey of redesigning the human
presence on earth to human impact on
earth from being degenerative and
exploitative to being regenerative and
collaborative then there might not be a
future for our species on this planet so
it's literally about human survival
[Applause]
I'm choosing to be hopeful
I could be distraught and say we don't
have a future but that's not a way to
live into the future and I feel that
there is a weather point of inflection
where the planetary immune response life
wants to continue and we through us
through human beings moving into this
regenerative design frame and becoming
part of the regeneration rising there's
still a chance that we can make it but
we have to start today
[Music]